Guide to the Charles W. Poletti Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Charles W. Poletti papers,
1865-1991
[Bulk: 1923-1970].
Poletti, Charles, 1903-2002.
32 linear feet ( 59 document boxes; 3 file card boxes; 16 oversize boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#1013
4078522
This collection documents the personal and political life of Charles Poletti, lawyer, politician, and the 46th governor of the State of New York. Poletti also served as an allied military governor in Italy during and after World War II.
Biographical Note
Charles Waldo Poletti was born on July 2, 1903 in Barre, Vermont. His parents, Dino and Carolina Gervasini Poletti, were both Italian immigrants, and his father worked as a stonecutter in a granite quarry. As a student at Barre High School, Poletti distinguished himself academically and socially. Well respected within the community, he was offered the opportunity to manage a store after graduation, but his principal encouraged him to apply to college. He won a scholarship to Harvard and supported himself in Cambridge, Massachusetts, by tending furnaces, waiting tables, and tutoring. In 1924, he graduated suma cum laude and a member of Phi Beta Kappa. He then attended the University of Rome on the Eleonora Duse Fellowship and took classes in Spain. Poletti returned to study at Harvard Law School, graduating with an L.L.B. in 1928.
Poletti joined the New York law firm Davis, Polk, Wardwell, Gardiner, & Reed, which was headed by 1924 Presidential Candidate John W. Davis. He worked as an attorney until 1930, when he took a position as legal assistant to the St. Lawrence Power Development Commission. He took an interest in political affairs and worked in the 1928 presidential campaign of Al Smith, and then served as a counsel to the Democratic National Committee in 1932.
Governor Herbert H. Lehman named Poletti as his counsel in 1933, where he soon became the governor's trusted aid. Poletti headed the 1935 Conference on Crime and advised on issues of crime and welfare. In 1937, Lehman appointed Poletti justice of the New York State Supreme Court, and he was elected in the fall for a full fourteen-year term. At 33, he was one of the youngest to hold the position. A year later, however, Poletti resigned, taking a $12,000 loss in salary to run alongside Lehman as lieutenant governor. Poletti held the position from 1939 to 1942.
After Lehman's retirement in 1942, Poletti served as the 46th governor of the State of New York for 29 days until the newly elected Thomas E. Dewey took office. Although his term was very brief--the shortest of any New York governor--he was praised for his work; on his final day of office, he presented a program calling for a "Beveridge Commission" to handle social security planning after World War II.
Several days after Dewey took office, Poletti became an assistant to War Secretary Henry L. Stimpson, and received a commission as a lieutenant colonel. He worked for the Allied Military Government (AMG) for the rest of the war, serving as allied military governor of, successively, Sicily, Naples, Rome, Milan, and Lombardy, from 1943 to 1945. He was selected both for his understanding of politics and law and his Italian ancestry, which the Army hoped would help him relate to the Italian population.
After returning to the U.S., Poletti became a trustee of the Power Authority of the State of New York (1955-1960). The New York Power Authority's plant in Astoria, Queens, was named after him.
In 1960, Poletti became Vice President for International Relations at the 1964 New York World's Fair. He was responsible for overseeing the fair's international exhibits.
Over the course of his career, Poletti was awarded many honors, including the Legion of Merit (U.S.A.); Officer of Order of British Empire; Knight Grand Cross of Order of Crown of Italy; Commander of Papal Order of St. Gregory the Great; First Order of the Star of Jordan; Grand Officer of Order of St. Agatha (San Marino); and the Gold Medal of the City of Rome. He was also made an Honorary Citizen of Naples, Rome, and Milan.
Poletti died in 2002 at the age of 99.
Scope and Content
The collection contains personal and professional material spanning most of Poletti's life, documenting his education at Harvard, his political career, and his military appointments in Italy. It also contains personal correspondence, family papers, and a small amount of information on his wife, Jean E. Poletti. Materials include correspondence, notes, academic papers, speeches, diaries, articles, ephemera, press releases, articles, clippings, certificates and plaques, photographs, and audio and film reels.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into thirteen series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1965-1982
Series II: Subject Files, 1910-1991
Series III: Harvard College and Law School, 1920-1928
Series IV: Legal Briefs, 1940-1964
Series V: Speeches and Press Releases, 1937-1947
Series VI: General, undated
Series VII: Jean E. Poletti Papers, 1931-1964
Series VIII: Articles by and about Charles Poletti, circa 1930-1970
Series IX: Photographs, 1920-1983
Series X: Memorabilia, circa 1915-1965
Series XI: Audiotapes and Films (New York World's Fair), 1939-1964
Series XII: Records, 1937-1964
Series XIII: Clipping Books, 1933-1948
.
Subjects
Allied Military Government.; Herbert H. Lehman Collections (Columbia University).; New York State Defense Council.; New York State War Council.; New York World's Fair (1964-1965); New York (State).--Governor.; New York (State).--Office of the Lieutenant Governor.; New York (State).--Supreme Court.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1865-1950.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1951-; Italy--History--Allied occupation, 1943-1947.; Electric power production.; World War, 1939-1945--Italy.; Photoprints.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1972 Correspondence, subject files, speeches, clippings, photographs, memorabilia Poletti, Charles gift
1982 Papers Poletti, Charles gift
Gift of Charles Poletti, November 1972.
Related Material
Herbert H. Lehman Papers Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Columbia University
Finding Aid available in repository and online; folder level control.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1865-1982
  This series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence in English and Italian and spans much of Poletti's life. While some of the material relates to his work and discusses specific bills or laws, most of the material is more personal in nature, and consists of letters of congratulation, invitations, and short notes and letters from friends, family, and political figures. Some letters are accompanied by photographs of Poletti at public events. Correspondence is filed alphabetically by name of individual or institution. Documents filed under Poletti's name consist of correspondence with Who's Who and many articles that provide basic biographical information.
  - A-Ame, 1937-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amp-Av, 1942-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1945-1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ahepa, Order of, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aiken, George D., 1941-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alfange, Dean, 1940-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1935-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Labor Party, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Legion, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Angell, Montgomery B., 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Anfuso, Victor L., 1939-1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Antonini, Luigi, 1939-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Association of Towns, 1941-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ba, 1937-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Babcock, H.E., 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Backer, George, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Baldelli, Ferdinando, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barton, Bruce, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Batista, Fulgencio, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Battle, George Gordon, 1938-1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Be, 1942-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Beaverbrook, Lord, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Benton, William, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Berle, Adolf A., Jr., 1937-1955 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bernays, Edward L., 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bernstein, Henri, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bertolini, Captain Edoardo G., 1940 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bi, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bianchi, Adele and Carlo, 1939-1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Biddle, Francis, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bingham, Jonathan B., 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bl, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bo, 1940-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Boland, John P., 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bonbright, James C., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Botein, Bernard, 1942-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Brandeis, Louis D., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Brick Presbyterian Church, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Broun, Heywood, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Earl L., 1938-1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Brownell, George A., 1937-1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brownell, Herbert, Jr., 1932-1952 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Br, 1933-1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bu, 1937-1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ca, 1934-1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Carson, Ralph, 1928-1942 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Carter, Elmer A., 1940-1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Carusi, Ugo, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ce, 1941-1955 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ch, 1936-1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Ci, 1940-1955 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Cl, 1939-1958 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cliff Haven--Catholic Summer School, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Co, 1937-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1941-1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conti, Piero, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Corscadden, Arthur, 1933-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Corsi, Edward, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cr, 1942-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cray, E.F., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Criscuolo, Luigi, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Crugnola, Dino and Family, 1953-1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cu-Cz, 1937-1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cummings, Homer, 1936-1942 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Curran, Edward Lodge, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - D, 1937-1970 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Daffinee, Dr. and Mrs. Ralph, 1922-1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - D'Amanda, Francis J., 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Daru, Robert, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Davidson, Maurice P., 1941-1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Davis, John W., 1940-1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - De Chambrun, Rene, 1932-1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Democratic County Committee, 1936-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1932-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Democratic State Committee, 1937-1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Desmond, Charles S., 1942-1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Desmond, Thomas C., 1937-1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dewey, Thomas E., 1936-1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Diamond, Milton, 1941-1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dodge, Eleanor, 1941-1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dubinsky, David, 1940-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - E, 1942-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Eastman, Edward R., 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ellis, J. William, 1934-1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - F, 1940-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 13 to 14)
  - Farley, James A., 1931-1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Foley, Edward H., Jr., 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1941-1960 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1928-1965, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Freeman, Fulton and Family, 1942-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Freidin, Jesse, 1938-1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Friendly, Henry J., 1927-1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - G-Goe, 1940-1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Gol-Gu, 1937-1942 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Galeazzi, Enrico Pietro, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Glueck, Sheldon, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Griswold, Erwin, 1954-1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Gutman, Daniel, 1942-1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Ha, 1937-1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Hanley, Joe R., 1939-1942 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 1941-1973 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Harvard University
    - Harvard College and Law School, 1920-1955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Graduation Clippings, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Class of 1924, 1924-1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Harvard Fund Contributions, 1940-1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Board of Overseers, 1937-1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Hayes, Patrick, Cardinal, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - He, 1938-1955 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Heck, Oswald D., 1941-1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Heming, Lucile W. (Later, Koshland, L.W.), 1931-1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Henricks, Mrs. Walter A. and Tonawanda Indians, 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Herrick, Elinore M., 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Herzog, Paul M., 1937-1957 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Herzstein, Harold L., 1935-1958 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Hi, 1940-1959 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Hillman, Sidney, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Ho, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hopkins, Harry, 1939-1942 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hu-Hz, 1937-1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hudson, Manley O.,1928-1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - I, 1937-1959 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ingegnieros, Jack, 1935-1942 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Inglis, Ellen, 1921-1922 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Italy America Society, 1924-1928 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - J, 1937-1955 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, Robert H., 1935-1940 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, Harold B., 1938-1944 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Jones, Eugene Kinckle, 1937-1946 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - K, 1937-1955 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Kiendl, Mr. and Mrs. Theodore, 1942-1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Klaus, Erwin H., 1940-1942 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Kopple, Robert, 1956-1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Kuhn, Delia W. and Ferdinand, Jr., 1934-1979 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - La, 1937-1951 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Ladd, Carl E. (New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell), 1937-1942 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello--Campaign Fliers, circa 1942 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello, 1934-1942 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lamont, Corliss, 1930-1983, (3 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 2 to 4)
  - Lamont, Eleanor, 1924-1948 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lamont, Thomas S., 1928-1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lamont, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas W., 1924-1948 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Le, 1939-1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Legion for American Unity, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lehman, Edith A., 1932-1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1933-1942, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 11 to 12)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.--New York Executive Chamber Documents Signed to Poletti, 1936 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1943-1963, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 1 to 2)
  - Lehman, Irving, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Levitt, Arthur, 1954-1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lexington Democratic Club, 1953-1959 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Li, 1941-1967 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lo, 1929-1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1950-1953 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Longworth, Alice Roosevelt, 1931-1933 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lu-Lz, 1939-1974 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Luce, Clare Booth, 1933-1944 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Lyons, Gerald,1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Ma, 1934-1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Marshall, Thurgood, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Mc, 1934-1942 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - McCloy, John J.,1942-1966 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Me, 1937-1959 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Mead, James M., 1938-1942 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Meany, George, 1935-1974 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Mi, 1939-1956 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Miller, Frieda S., 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Millonzi, Robert I., 1942-1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mills, Saul, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mo, 1933-1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Monod, Philippe, 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Morrow, Dwight W. and Elizabeth C., 1927-1930 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Morrow, Elizabeth R., 1929-1934 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Morse, David A., 1944-1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Moses, Robert, 1952-1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Moynihan, Daniel P.,1955-1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Mu-My, 1942-1955 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - N, 1942-1964 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (N.A.A.C.P.), 1939-1966 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1938-1941 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - National Council of Young Israel, 1939-1941 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - National Lawyers Guild, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Neufeld, Maurice F., 1941-1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The New Republic, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - New York State Council of Churches, 1940-1942 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New York Stock Exchange, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Niles, David K., 1942-1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - O, 1937-1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - O'Dwyer, William, 1942-1949 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Orlando, Vittorio, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Ottman, William, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Pa, 1936-1960 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Palladino, Giuseppe, 1949-1965 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Parri, Feruccio, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Pe, 1937-1953 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Perkins, Frances, 1936-1965 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Ph-Pm, 1942-1957 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Po, 1937-1957 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Poletti, Carla Knox (Mrs. Kyril R. Tidmarsh), 1942-1960 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Poletti Family Correspondence, 1865-1875 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Poletti, Carolina G. (Mother), 1922-1978 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Poletti, Charles (Box 12, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Biographical Information, 1924-1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1929-1969, (3 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Correspondence with Cousins, 1929-1956 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Friends from Barre, Vermont, 1920-1924 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Personal and Financial Affairs, 1928-1966 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Personal and Financial Affairs, 1930-1939 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Vermont Background, 1922-1973 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Personal and Financial (Elizabethtown, NJ), 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "Self Analysis of Personal Traits," 1924 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Vermont Background, 1922-1973 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Poletti, Charles Ellis, 1938-1979 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Poletti, Charles Ellis--Clippings, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Poletti, Dino (Grandfather) and Poletti, Maria Cavigioli (Grandmother), 1890-1895 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Poletti, Dino (Father), 1922 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Poletti, Jean Knox, 1939-1974, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Poletti, Jean Knox--Clippings, 1940-1944 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Poletti, Jean Knox--Clippings,1974 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Poletti, Joanna Shattuck, 1941-1965 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Polier, Justine Wise, 1926-1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Polk, Frank L., 1937-1942 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Pope, Generoso, 1940-1946 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Pope, Paul VI, 1944-1958 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1942 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Pr-Pu, 1937-1973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Prendergast, Michael H., 1956-1960 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Q, 1939-1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - R, 1937-1978 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Rabin, Benjamin J., 1937-1968 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, 1941-1966 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1953-1967 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1940-1964 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin, D., 1930-1955 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Rose, Alex, 1938-1966 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Rosenberg, Anna M., 1940-1950 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Rosenman, Samuel I., 1937-1966 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Rossini, Vincenzo, 1937-1942 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Sa, 1939-1958 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Sc, 1939-1960 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Schlesinger, Emil, 1938-1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Schwarz, Frederick A.O., 1938-1981 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Se-Sf, 1939-1958 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sforza, Count Carlo, 1941-1943 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Sh, 1937-1958 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Shattuck, Mr. and Mrs. John and Family, 1941-1963 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Shientag, Florence Perlow, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Si, 1942-1954 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Sk-Sn, 1936-1955 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Alfred E., 1938-1944 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - So-Sp, 1935-1959 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Sobel, Nathan R., 1939-1960 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Spano, Olga Albasini--Poletti Bust, 1953-1963 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Spellman, Francis Cardinal, 1939-1964 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Spofford, Charles M., 1928-1967 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - St, 1937-1966 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E., 1952-1961 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1943-1946 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Stone, Harlan Fiske, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Strebel, Gustave A., 1940-1942 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Su-Sy, 1942-1978 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1936-1948 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - T, 1936-1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Taussig, F.W., 1924-1935 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Taylor, Myron C., 1944-1947 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1958-1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Presidents, 1958-1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - U, 1938-1958 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - V, 1939-1967 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Van Schaick, George S., 1937-1942 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Veiller, Lawrence, 1937-1939, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 10 to 11)
  - Wa, 1937-1942 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Wagner, Robert F., Jr., 1942-1968 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Wagner, Robert F., Sr.,1937-1942 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Ward, Ivy (Estate), 1939-1942 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Wardwell, Allen, 1931-1953 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Watt, Murray L., 1941-1957 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - We, 1937-1966 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Weinberger, Howard, 1939-1955 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Weinfeld, Edward, 1948-1982 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Wh, 1930-1958 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - White, Walter, 1937-1942 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - White, William Allen, 1940-1973 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Wi, 1929-1960 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Wickersham, Cornelius W., 1939-1942 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Willkie, Wendell L., 1940-1944 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Wilson, Charles E. ("Electric"), 1941-1948 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Wo--Cartoon signed by Denys Wortman, undated (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Wo, 1937-1977 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Wu-Wy, 1937-1939 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - X, 1937-1942 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Y, 1939-1957 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Young, Owen D.,1941 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Young Men's Board of Trade, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Z, 1942-1974 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Series II: Subject Files, 1910-1991